Guide to the Facilities Department records, 1904-2008 RG0063
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Departmental files, 1904-2008; RG0063 Series 10; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 3, Box 2, Box 4)
  - Buildings - general - National Register of Historic Places nominations, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Buildings - general - Space Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Buildings - general - Space Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Buildings - general - Space Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Buildings - 1st Columbian College bldg., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Buildings - 2003 G St., NW, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Buildings - 2000 Pennsylvania Ave, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Buildings - Academic Cluster, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Buildings - Airlie House, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Buildings - Alumni Hall, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Buildings - Alumni House, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Buildings - Architects, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Buildings - Bacon Hall, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Buildings - Burns Law Library (716 20th St., NW), 1966-1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Buildings - Concoran Hall, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Buildings - Concoran Hall - Dedication (October 28, 1924), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Buildings - Eye Street (1528-#15380 on north side of street between 16th Street & Vermont Avenue) - photo source materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Buildings - F Street Club, 1976-1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Buildings - F Street Club, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Scope and Contents
    This folder includes an image with the following data written on the image "PB-7 1925 F St. (Home of F St. Club) reproduced from W.B. Bryan Collection, Prints and Photographs No. 7077"
  - Buildings - Funger Hall, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Buildings - Gelman Library, 1973-2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Buildings - Hall of Government (1938) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Buildings - Health and Wellness Center, 1999-2004 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Buildings - Law School Building - 700 20th Street - dedication program and remarks, March 8, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Buildings - Law School Building (1435 K St., NW), 1920-1925 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Buildings - laying of cornerstones, 1951-1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Buildings - Lenthall Houses, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Buildings - Lerner Hall, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Buildings - Lisner Auditorium, 1976 ca.-1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Buildings - Lisner Library (2023 G St.), 1939-1951 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Buildings - Marvin Center, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Buildings - Media and Public Affairs Building, 03/07/2001-02/20/2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Buildings - naming of buildings, 09/09/1963-02/08/1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Buildings - National Law Center, 1960 ca. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Buildings - Paul Himmelfarb Health Sciences Library, 02/15/1971-07/1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Buildings - Plaques, 10/18/1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Buildings - President's House 1868-69, 10/18/1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Buildings - proposed buildings - plans and architecture, 1904-1907 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Buildings - Red Lion Row, 06/30/1980-11/24/1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Buildings - Rome Hall, 01/23/1984-03/19/1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Buildings - Ross Hall - dedication, 02/15/1971-05/24/1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Buildings - Smith Center, 11/21/1972-02/19/1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Buildings - Stockton Hall, 05/28/1968-09/1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Buildings - Stockton Hall - dedication, November 14, 1925, 10/1925-11/14/1925 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Buildings - Tin Tabernacle (1926-1926) (old gym), 05/01/1925-04/01/1926 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Buildings - Tompkins Hall - Vault for the Future, 01/01/1947-02/21/2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Buildings - University Building (15th & H Street, SE corner 1884-1910), 1884-02/1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Buildings - University Library (2130 H St.), 09/05/1967-02/15/1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Buildings - University Library (2130 H Street) - dedication ceremony, October 13, 1973, 08/23/1973-10/13/1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Buildings - University parking garage, 22nd & H Streets, 11/1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Buildings - Virginia campus, 10/1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Buildings - Women's Activities Building (1946 - ), 02/1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Buildings - Woodhull House, 09/1989-01/26/2001 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Buildings and property, 09/1989-01/26/2001 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Campus construction projects, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Campus development plans - Campus Amenities Plan (1993) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Campus development plans, 1974-2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Campus development plans - Campus Plan for 1985-2000 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Campus development plans - Campus Plan for 2000-2010, 12/28/1999 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Campus development plans - Campus Plan for 2006-2025, volume 1, 02/16/2006 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Campus development plans - Campus Plan for 2006-2025, volume 2, 02/16/2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Campus Graphics Manual, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Campus maps of GWU - 1920-1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Campus maps of GWU - 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Campus maps of GWU - 1976 - 2004 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Campus maps of GWU - artists' depiction of GWU and environs, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Campus maps of GWU - walking tours, 1969 - 2008 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cemetery lots owned by University, 1969 ca.-1971 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - History of GW 1901-1920 Drawings of proposed buildings, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - History of GW 1961-1980- Energy Crisis At GW, 11/08/1973-04/12/1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Physical plant, 03/15/1919-02/01/1988 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Physical plant - grounds, 03/19/1941-03/20/1941 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Physical plant - recycling, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - University gates, 10/23/1996-05/29/1998 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Campus plan historic landmarks [1/3], 1987; Series 10 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Campus plan historic landmarks [2/3], 1987; Series 10 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Campus plan historic landmarks [3/3], 1987; Series 10 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Mount Vernon Campus construction photographs, Circa 2000-2003; Series 11; 0.75 Linear Feet 2 document boxes
  Arrangement
  Arranged in no particular order.
  The images in this series are of different construction projects on the Mount Vernon campus and date from circa 2000-2003. There are images of what the campus looked like prior to construction, during construction, and some following completion of projects. Some of these projects include interior renovations as well as construction of new facilities and renovations of existing facilities. The list of buildings included in these images include: MVC Pub, Pelham, Somers Residence Hall, Hensley Residence Hall, Clark Residence Hall, Cole Residence Hall, Acheson Science Center, Webb Hall, Florence Hollis Hand Chapel, Dorothy Williamson Clock Tower, Lloyd Gymnasium, GW Police Gatehouse, Merriweather Residence Hall, Softball Field, the swimming Pool, the Soccer and Athletic Field complex.
  Dates of project completions
  Soccer field/Athletics/Garage/tennis court/clock tower 2000-02 Somers Hall addition 2000-01 Softball field 2001-02 Lloyd gym addition (or renovation 2003(?) Cole Hall renovation 2000-01 Acheson renovation 2002 (?)
  This information was supplied by facilities staff member Alex Wells on May 21, 2012.
  - Construction images [Green photograph album [1/2]], Circa 2000-2003; Series 11 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    The images in this folder cover construction projects has images that show many buildings both old (renovated and demolished) and new on the campus. Some of these buildings include MVC Pub, Pelham, Somers Residence Hall, Hensley Residence Hall, Cole Residence Hall, Acheson Science Center, Webb Hall, Florence Hollis Hand Chapel, Merriweather Residence Hall, Softball Field, the Soccer and Athletic Field complex.
  - Construction images [Green photograph album [2/2]], Circa 2000-2003; Series 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Construction images [Dark Blue photograph album], Circa 2000-2003; Series 11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    The images in this folder cover construction projects has images that show many buildings both old (renovated and demolished) and new on the campus. Some of these projects in this photograph album include renovations of Somers Residence Hall, Ames Hall, Softball Field, Tennis Courts, the Soccer and Athletic Field complex.
  - Construction images [Light Blue photograph album], Circa 2000-2003; Series 11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    The images in this folder cover construction projects has images that show many buildings both old (renovated and demolished) and new on the campus. Some of these buildings include Somers Residence Hall, Ames Hall, Softball Field, Tennis Courts, the Soccer and Athletic Field complex.
  - Construction images [Brown photograph album [1/2]], Circa 2000-2003; Series 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Construction images [Brown photograph album [2/2]], Circa 2000-2003; Series 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mount Vernon campus Aerial photograph, undated; Series 11 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Renovation various projects, 1994 Summer; Series 11 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Written on the original photograph album "George Emerald Contracting, Renovation, alteration painting/plastering electrical/waterproofing at various dorms interior and exterior campus wide"